Finding Aid for American Legion, Dept. of Michigan records, 1919-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
American Legion, Dept. of Michigan records 1919-1999
American Legion. Dept. of Michigan.
85590 Be.2 2; Be Outsize; mf 525c-532c
State component of larger national organization serving interests of war-time veterans. Series include meeting minutes, annual reports, convention proceedings, constitution and by-laws, records of American Legion Hospital, and records of various youth programs and other community service projects.
18 linear feet
8 oversize volumes
1 oversize folders
8 microfilms
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated to the library by the Michigan Department of the American Legion (donor no. 4282 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The record group is open to research.
The origins of the American Legion can be traced to the late stages of World War 1, as American servicemen began to contemplate the formation of "an organization of veterans, dedicated in peace to the same ideals that inspired their services in war." Central to this effort was the comradeship characteristic of the soldiers that comprised the American Expeditionary Force. Wanting to preserve friendships that had been forged both in training camps and on the fields of battle, 500 delegates, representing various units of the A.E.F., were gathered in Paris in March 1919 to sow the seeds of the proposed veterans organization. This gathering, known as the Paris Caucus, arrived at the name "The American Legion" for the new organization, and set forth plans for a second caucus, at which further details of the organization would be ironed out. This second caucus was held in St. Louis in May of 1919, and involved nearly 1000 delegates from across the United States. It was at this event that the constitution and by-laws of the organization were adopted, the preamble drafted, and the location of the first annual convention determined.
The history of the Michigan department of the American Legion can be traced to April 1919, shortly after the Paris Caucus. At a meeting in New York, Colonel Fred M. Alger was appointed Chairman of the Michigan Temporary Committee. Later in that same year, forty-six Michigan delegates were selected for the St. Louis Caucus, and while in St. Louis, the Michigan Department held its first meeting in the Hotel Statler. At this point, George C. Waldo was named Temporary Chairman, Benjamin B. Bellows Temporary Vice Commander, and Lyle B. Tabor Temporary Adjutant.
The Michigan Department expanded rapidly, and by July of that year, 45 posts, representing 2,088 members, had been granted charters with seven more in progress. The first State Convention was held in Grand Rapids in October 1920, with Colonel A.H. Gansser named State Commander and Lyle Tabor State Adjutant. By this time, Michigan had 192 Posts covering every county in the state. Over time, the membership requirements were altered to include any American war-time veterans, not just World War 1. As a result, the organization continued to grow with new veterans and thrive through the 20th century. It is interesting to note that with this expansive membership, neutrality in regard to partisan politics has long been the stance of the Michigan Department. While the Department enjoys a positive working relationship with the Michigan State government, its key focuses remain veteran's issues rather than political parties.
In addition to representing the interests of veterans, the Michigan Department of the American Legion takes part in a number of projects that are generally of benefit to its members and the surrounding community. The Department operated a hospital and planned living community in Battle Creek, respectively named the American Legion Hospital and Legion Villa. Various scholarships for "deserving students" are offered by the Department, namely, the Brewer Trust and the William Morris Scholarship. Additionally, the Department is involved in youth programs such as Boys State, a summer program where high school students simulate a state government, the American Legion Junior Baseball League, and, until the late 1970s a home for the children of veterans located in Otter Lake, Michigan.
The records of the Michigan department of the American Legion date from the early days of the department in 1919 up to the late 1990s, and document the internal functions of the organization as well as various projects and community service programs undertaken by the department. The record group contains the following series: Executive Committee Files, Proceedings and Annual Reports, Publications, Assorted Meeting Minutes, Michigan Department Annual Reports, Cancelled Post Files, Other Records, Otter Lake Children's Billet, Scrapbooks and Photograph Albums, and Sound Recording. Portions of the records are available on microfilm only.
Subjects:
Veterans--Michigan--Societies, etc.; American Legion. Dept. of Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Executive Committee Files 1918-1982
  Executive Committee Files (1919-1982, 4.5 rolls of microfilm, 6 linear feet) largely consist of the minutes of meetings held by the executive committee.
  - 1919-1923 (Reel 1)
  - 1924-1929 (Reel 2)
  - 1930-1932 (Reel 3)
  - 1933-1939 (Reel 4)
  - 1940-1941 (Reel 5)
  - 1941-1953 (Box 1)
  - 1954-1962 (Box 2)
  - 1963-1969 (Box 3)
  - 1970-July 1975 (Box 4)
  - August 1975-1978 (Box 5)
  - 1979-1982 (Box 6)
- Proceedings and Annual Reports 1921-1982
  Proceedings and Annual Reports (1921-1982, 3.5 rolls of microfilm, 3 linear feet) detail the proceedings of annual conventions with reports from various committees, and remarks from notable Legion personalities.
  - 1921-1924 (Reel 5)
  - 1925-1931 (Reel 6)
  - 1932-1936 (Reel 7)
  - 1937-1941 (Reel 8)
  - 1942-1958 (Box 7)
  - 1959-1973 (Box 8)
  - 1974-1982 (Box 9)
- Publications 1923-1961
  The Publications (1923-1961, 0.25 linear feet) gathered are comprised principally of commemorative programs from conventions as well as publications detailing legion programs such as Boy's State and Junior Baseball.
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 10)
- Assorted Meeting Minutes 1926-1978
  Assorted Meeting Minutes (1926-1978, 0.25 linear feet) consist of the meeting minutes of various committees such as the Welfare Committee, Administrative Committee, and Veteran's Housing Committee.
  - Welfare Committee and Joint Meetings with Other Committees
    - Meeting Minutes December 1926-July 1931 (Box 10)
    - Meeting Minutes December 1926-August 1930 (Box 10)
  - Administrative Committee
    - Meeting Minutes September 8, 1945 (Box 10)
    - Meeting Minutes March 12, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Administrative Committee & Hospital Committee: Meeting Minutes November 23, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Veterans Housing Committee: Meeting Minutes October 25, 1946 (Box 10)
- Michigan Department Annual Convention Reports 1919-1948
  The Michigan Department Annual Convention Reports (1919-1948, 0.5 linear feet) are published collections of reports regarding a number of issues presented by various committees at the annual conventions held by the department.
  - 1st Annual Convention October 1919 (Box 10)
  - 10th Annual Convention September 1928, Photocopy (Box 10)
  - 11th Annual Convention September 1929 (Box 10)
  - 12th Annual Convention July 1930 (Box 10)
  - 13th Annual Convention July 1931, Photocopy (Box 10)
  - 14th Annual Convention August 1932 (Box 10)
  - 15th Annual Convention August 1933, Photocopy (Box 10)
  - 16th Annual Convention September 1934, Photocopy (Box 10)
  - 17th Annual Convention August 1935, Photocopy (Box 10)
  - 18th Annual Convention August 1936, Photocopy (Box 10)
  - 19th Annual Convention August 1937 (Box 10)
  - 20th Annual Convention August 1938 (Box 10)
  - 21st Annual Convention August 1939 (Box 10)
  - 22nd Annual Convention August 1940 (Box 10)
  - 23rd Annual Convention August 1941 (Box 10)
  - 24th Annual Convention August 1942 (Box 10)
  - 28th Annual Convention August 1946 (Box 10)
  - 30th Annual Convention August 1948 (Box 10)
- Cancelled Post Files, 1919-1999
  Cancelled Post Files (1919-1990s, 6 linear feet) contain information, in varying degrees of detail, concerning individual posts. These include applications for charters, member lists, photographs, etc.
  - Addison
    - #243-Omans-Ewing (Box 11)
  - Adrian
    - #383-Dorie Miller (Box 11)
    - #399-Delmar H. Daniels (Box 11)
    - #432-Nick Alexander Post (African American) (Box 11)
  - Alba
    - #263-Dorus F. Boback (Box 11)
  - Albion
    - #114-Will Curtis (African American) (Box 11)
  - Algonac
    - #202-Pemberton Bros. (Box 11)
  - Allenville
    - #285-Herbert Connors Summerby (Box 11)
  - Alma
    - #132-Geo. W. Meyers (Box 11)
    - #164-Meyers-Smith (Box 11)
  - Almont
    - #339-Dodge Whitehead (Box 11)
  - Alpha
    - #246-Thomas Farrell (Box 11)
  - Alto
    - #166-Alexander Anderson (Box 11)
  - Ann Arbor
    - #303-University (Box 11)
    - #357-Kelley-Sanders (Box 11)
    - #394-Geo. Ham Cannon (Box 11)
    - #398-Kelley-Sanders (African American) (Box 11)
    - #572-Ann Arbor-Pittsfield (Box 11)
  - Atlanta
    - #245-James Wall (Box 11)
  - Augusta
    - #323-John Grier (Box 11)
    - #332-Leroy Redmond (Box 11)
  - Bad Axe
    - #96-Bad Axe (Box 11)
  - Bancroft
    - #161-Chas. A. Rorabeck (Box 11)
  - Bannister
    - #451-Maple River (Box 11)
  - Baraga
    - #315-Baraga (Box 11)
  - Barryton
    - #327-Hight Bloomquist (Box 11)
  - Battle Creek
    - #383-Oscer Burnette (Box 11)
    - #429-Valentine Braxton (Box 11)
    - #558-Dennis McKeen (Box 11)
    - #567-James Chatman (Box 11)
  - Bear Lake
    - #317-Cirenus E. McCary (Box 11)
  - Belleville
    - #132-Belleville (Box 11)
    - #258-Lincoln (Box 11)
  - Bellevue
    - #114-Maynard J. Hewitt (Box 11)
  - Benzonia-Beulah
    - #345-Charles L. Joy (Box 11)
  - Berkley
    - #371-Berkley (Box 11)
  - Beulah
    - #496-Benzie County (Box 11)
  - Bloomingdale
    - #169-Warren Gaines (Box 11)
  - Bravo
    - #273-Marshal-Nelson (Box 11)
  - Breedsville
    - #336-Albert Hasier (Box 11)
  - Brimley
    - #70-Alfred J. LeBlanc (Box 11)
  - Brooklyn
    - #63-Wilbur-Bartlett (Box 11)
  - Brown City
    - #214-Potter Poth (Box 11)
  - Burr Oak
    - #247-Walter Mayer (Box 11)
  - Carson City
    - #130-Douglas K. McGloskey (Box 11)
  - Caspian
    - #368-Purgato-Piper (Box 11)
  - Cass City
    - #187-Adams Seeger (Box 11)
    - #507-Tri-County (Box 11)
  - Cassopolis
    - #249-Charis (African American) (Box 11)
    - #403-Howard Clark (African American) (Box 11)
  - Camp Custer
    - #88-Camp Custer (Box 11)
  - Centerline
    - #81-Stevens-Meyers (Box 11)
    - #478-Capt. F. F. Foster U.S.N. (Box 11)
  - Centerville
    - #124-Andrew N. Welsh (Box 11)
  - Central Lake
    - #319-Andrew N. Welsh (Box 11)
  - Champion
    - #556-Champion (Box 11)
  - Chesaning
    - #67-Arthur Thayer (Box 11)
  - Clare
    - #128-Clare (Box 11)
  - Clarksville
    - #201-Geo. A. Merrill (Box 11)
  - Clawson
    - #19-Mattimore Cleary (Box 11)
  - Clio
    - #200-Neely Lebar (Box 11)
  - Coleman
    - #207-George Edward Young (Box 11)
  - Colon
    - #167-Russell E. Welty (Box 11)
  - Columbiaville
    - #132-Columbiaville (Box 11)
  - Concord
    - #328-Simons (Box 11)
    - #394-Bailey-Fisher-Zeller (Box 11)
  - Conway
    - #329-David Zurcher (Box 11)
  - Curtis
    - #371-Curtis (Box 11)
  - Dearborn
    - #427-Campbell Loverix South End Post (Box 11)
  - Decatur
    - #309-Decatur (Box 11)
  - Deerfield
    - #248-Elwood D Stansbury (Box 11)
  - Detroit
    - #1-Charles A. Learned (Box 11)
    - #13-Ragan-Lide (Box 11)
    - #19-Chevrolet-Detroit (Box 11)
    - #23-Century (Box 11)
    - #70-Holley Carburetor (Box 11)
    - #70-National Guard-Iron Fist (Box 11)
    - #75-Detroit Fire Department-Arthur R. Peltier (Box 11)
    - #81-A.R.D. (Box 11)
    - #99-Union Labor (Box 11)
    - #118-Arthur Posselius (Box 11)
    - #119-Bearl V. Pittenger (Box 11)
    - #124-Edwin Denby (Box 11)
    - #125-Bishop-Middleditch (Box 11)
    - #128-St. Lawrence (Box 12)
    - #130-Theodor & Quentin Roosevelt (Box 12)
    - #134-N.Y. Central System (Box 12)
    - #136-23rd Engineers (Box 12)
    - #149-Harold Todd (Box 12)
    - #166-Ternstedt (Box 12)
    - #166-Detroit Motorbus Company (Box 12)
    - #185-Metropolitan (Box 12)
    - #191-City of Detroit (Box 12)
    - #193-Pontchartrain (Box 12)
    - #200-Thaddeus Kosciuszko (Box 12)
    - #201-Southwest (Box 12)
    - #201-Albert R. Barker (Box 12)
    - #210-University (Box 12)
    - #218-Julius Rosenwald (Box 12)
    - #224-Fort Wayne (Box 12)
    - #246-Communications (Box 12)
    - #249-Vickers (Box 12)
    - #251-Delray (Box 12)
    - #257-Detroit Aviation (Box 12)
    - #260-Westward (Box 12)
    - #262-Chrysler (Box 12)
    - #270-Pulaski (Box 12)
    - #275-Motor City (Box 12)
    - #276-John Marshall (Box 12)
    - #278-Christian (Box 12)
    - #284-Security (Box 12)
    - #291-Turnverein (Box 12)
    - #310-Thomas Jefferson (Box 12)
    - #313-Cecot-Park (Box 12)
    - #318-Naval (Box 12)
    - #327-College Park (Box 12)
    - #334-Antlers (Box 12)
    - #336-Vittel (Box 12)
    - #341-North Detroit (Box 12)
    - #349-General Wm. Mitchell (Box 12)
    - #349-Francis E. Dow (Box 12)
    - #351-Jos. P. Wesley (Box 12)
    - #358-Othello Crosby (African American) (Box 12)
    - #357-Hudson Motor Company (Box 12)
    - #358-Redford (Box 12)
    - #359-Harper-Van Dyke (Box 12)
    - #361-Red Arrow 32nd Division (Box 12)
    - #365-Advertising Men's (Box 12)
    - #370-Herbert R. McKinney (Box 12)
    - #371-Russell Johnson Theatrical (Box 12)
    - #373-Federal-Connor (Box 12)
    - #376-Island of Malta (Box 12)
    - #383-Leo R. Schaefer (Box 12)
    - #387-Chalmers (Box 12)
    - #395-Lohman Lincoln Motor (Box 12)
    - #404-Jacobs "Senne" (Box 12)
    - #404-Continental (Box 12)
    - #406-Detroit Lutheran (Box 12)
    - #412-Laurel J. Doyle (Box 12)
    - #414-The J. L. Hudson Co. (Box 12)
    - #415-George Earl Watson (Box 12)
    - #416-Packard Motor (Box 12)
    - #438-Bell Telephone (Box 12)
    - #440-Ex-Cell-O (Box 12)
    - #440-Rosedale Detroit (Box 12)
    - #442-Joey Moss (Box 12)
    - #443-Falcon (Box 12)
    - #450-Burke-Downey-Jones (Box 12)
    - #452-Lithuanian (Box 12)
    - #453-The Whitaker Paper Co. (Box 12)
    - #461-Grandale Detroit (Box 12)
    - #464-Gen. John J. Pershing Post (Box 12)
    - #466-William P. Oliver-Paul R. Walker (Box 13)
    - #469-Parke, Davis & Co. (Box 13)
    - #477-Molly Pitcher (Box 13)
    - #480-Beatty and Hannigan (Box 13)
    - #482-James Francis Neer (Box 13)
    - #485-Miller-Bommer-Marentette (Box 13)
    - #486-Michael J. Bokatzian (Box 13)
    - #492-Charles Mueller (Box 13)
    - #493-Franklin Delano Roosevelt (Box 13)
    - #495-Catholic Central (Box 13)
    - #498-Polish Century (Box 13)
    - #506-William D. Riley, Jr. (Box 13)
    - #508-Matthew A. Corrigan (Box 13)
    - #509-Cedar of Lebanon (Box 13)
    - #509-Howard Hudson (Box 13)
    - #520-Cunningham Drug Company (Box 13)
    - #542-Calvin & Stanley Elson (Box 13)
    - #546-Andrew J Starn Transportation (Box 13)
    - #548-Admiral Waesche (Box 13)
    - #551-Cadillac Motor Car (Box 13)
    - #553-Edwin Zielke (Box 13)
    - #555-Pontchartrain (Box 13)
    - #561-Internal Revenue (Box 13)
    - #564-Memorial Park (Box 13)
    - #567-Pfeiffer Brewing Company (Box 13)
    - #569-Linwood (Box 13)
    - #571-Cedar of Lebanon (Box 13)
  - Dexter
    - #84-Ralph Whitney (Box 13)
  - Dimondale
    - #276-Frank Zimmerman (Box 13)
    - #515-Dimondale (Box 13)
  - Diorite
    - #157-Nicholas Tassob (Box 13)
  - Dowagiac
    - #188-A. K. Richey (Box 13)
    - #381-A. K. Richey (Box 13)
  - Drummond
    - #140-Drummond Island (Box 13)
    - #501-Drummond Island (Box 13)
  - Durand
    - #151-Otis Raymond (Box 13)
  - Dutton
    - #565-Dutton (Box 13)
  - East Lansing
    - #283-Michigan State Police (Box 13)
    - #402-Michigan State College (Box 13)
  - Ecorse
    - #32-Roy E. Salliotte (Box 13)
    - #272-Great Lakes Steel (Box 13)
    - #352-Alexandre Dumas (African American) (Box 13)
    - #378-Walton H Walker (Box 13)
  - Edmore
    - #136-William Wylie (Box 13)
  - Elk Rapids
    - #251-Elk (Box 13)
  - Elsie
    - #275-Moore Huffman (Box 13)
  - Elwell
    - #198-Mahin-Langworthy (Box 13)
  - Emmett
    - #32-Smith McMullin (Box 13)
  - Engadine
    - #272-John Riley (Box 13)
  - Fairgrove
    - #318-Fred Balcom (Box 13)
  - Farwell
    - #370-Frizzell Stinchcomb (Box 13)
  - Fennville
    - #38-James DeWitt (Box 13)
    - #229-Marks Chelman (Box 13)
  - Ferndale
    - #383-Woodworth-Valentine (Box 13)
  - Fife Lake
    - #299-Burnett-Labar Nelson (Box 13)
    - #316-Fife Lake (Box 13)
  - Flint
    - #139-Benjamin Schubert Barber (African American) (Box 13)
    - #185-The Flintstone (Box 13)
    - #198-Maysoc Jarrett (Box 13)
    - #289-Jack Doyle (Box 13)
    - #299-Oden Post (African American) (Box 13)
    - #306-Dorie Miller (Box 13)
    - #339-Flint City (Box 13)
    - #453-Maxie H. Harris (Box 13)
    - #456-Clark-Durocher (Box 13)
    - #462-Gordon Walker (Box 14)
    - #464-Cady-Turner (Box 14)
    - #492-Flint Women's (Box 14)
    - #497-Chevrolet Post (Box 14)
    - #513-Flint Bell Telephone (Box 14)
    - #524-Charles E. Mabry (Box 14)
    - #534-Flint Chevrolet Motor (Box 14)
    - #560-Walter R. Reuther (Box 14)
  - Flushing
    - #378-Morrish-Labarge Post (Box 14)
  - Fostoria
    - #168-Griswold Gooch (Box 14)
    - #536-Griswold-Wheaton (Box 14)
  - Freeland
    - #349-Powley-Sarle (Box 14)
  - Gagetown
    - #208-Markel Sullivan (Box 14)
  - Garden
    - #132-Garden City (Box 14)
    - #273-Garden (Box 14)
    - #454-Garden Peninsula Post (Box 14)
  - Gaylord
    - #458-Top-O-Michigan Post (Box 14)
  - Genesee
    - #471-Genesee Township Post (Box 14)
  - Gladwin
    - #115-Wright (Box 14)
  - Globeville
    - #333-L. B. Van Voorheis (Box 14)
  - Goodrich
    - #539-Miller-Auten Post (Box 14)
  - Grand Junction
    - #405-Grand Junction (Box 14)
  - Grand Rapids
    - #243-Captain Edward Leonard (Box 14)
    - #273-PFC Milton Olive III (Box 14)
    - #277-West Side (Box 14)
    - #405-Grand Junction (Box 14)
    - #435-Henry A. Goss Post (Box 14)
    - #445-Ex-Service Women's Post (Box 14)
    - #472-Walker Post (Box 14)
    - #481-Five Star Post (Box 14)
    - #517-Gil Powers-Glen Dann Post (Box 14)
    - #521-Grand Rapids Labor (Box 14)
    - #529-Grand Rapids Aviation (Box 14)
    - #432-Metropolitan Post (Box 14)
  - Grant
    - #261-Leo H. Rogers (Box 14)
  - Greenland
    - #47-Harry Eva (Box 14)
    - #299-Kenneth E. Somero (Box 14)
  - Grosse Point
    - #497-Foley-VerVaecke-Knoll (Box 14)
  - Gwinn
    - #185-Gwinn (Box 14)
    - #425-Sather-Paris Post (Box 14)
  - Hamtramck
    - #24-Henry Bushway, Jr. (Box 14)
    - #198-Highland Park-North Detroit (Triangle) (African American) (Box 14)
    - #366-City of Hamtramck (Box 14)
    - #465-Washington-Chester-Miller (Box 14)
  - Hanover
    - #237-Howard-Ford (Box 14)
  - Harrisville
    - #56-Armstrong (Box 14)
  - Hermansville
    - #198-Charles Saxe (Box 14)
  - Hesperia
    - #300-Earl Sweet (Box 14)
  - Highland Park
    - #120-David M. Vincent (Box 14)
    - #329-Charles L. Edwards (Box 14)
    - #433-Ford-Highland Park Post (Box 14)
  - Hillman
    - #86-Milo Barton (Box 14)
  - Holland
    - #188-Holland Memorial Post (Box 14)
    - #512-Tulip City Post (Box 14)
  - Honor
    - #294-Leslie Tomlinson (Box 14)
  - Homer
    - #225-Hess & Whitcomb (Box 14)
  - Hope
    - #448-Braley-Henry Post (Box 14)
  - Houghton
    - #80-Judson B. Ingram (Box 14)
  - Howard City
    - #139-Fitzgerald Nelson (Box 14)
    - #263-Fitzgerald Nelson (Box 14)
  - Ishpeming
    - #58-Ishpeming (Box 14)
  - Ithaca
    - #237-Orin Riker (Box 14)
    - #328-Riker Furgason (Box 14)
  - Jackson
    - #178-Michigan Central R.R. (Box 14)
  - Kalamazoo
    - #334-Murdock (African American) (Box 14)
    - #428-The Outpost (Box 14)
    - #447-Phillips-Carr Post (African American) (Box 14)
    - #474-Hanes-Malloy Post (Box 14)
    - #513-Caroline Bartlett Crane Post (Box 14)
  - Kaleva
    - #324-J & E Wertenan (Box 14)
  - Kalkasa
    - #254-Burwell Wise (Box 14)
  - Kingston
    - #284-Barrett-Geliske (Box 14)
    - #534-Kingston (Box 14)
  - Laingsburg
    - #173-Clare Burt (Box 14)
  - Lake City
    - #288-Emory Sours (Box 14)
  - Lake Odessa
    - #122-LaVerne Demaray (Box 14)
  - Lakeview
    - #262-Ernest D. Wortley (Box 14)
  - Lambertville
    - #249-L. H. Komsteller (Box 14)
  - Lansing
    - #19-Lansing-Metro (Box 15)
    - #116-Capital City Tuebor (Box 15)
    - #188-George Washington Carver (Box 15)
    - #193-Tuebor (Box 15)
    - #397-Edward W. Strickland (Box 15)
    - #413-Reo (Box 15)
    - #423-Jacob Davenport (Box 15)
    - #462-Donald E. Hansen (Box 15)
    - #517-Lansing Bell Telephone Post (Box 15)
  - Leslie
    - #242-Wright Farrand (Box 15)
  - Levering
    - #179-Keller Thompson (Box 15)
  - Lexington
    - #298-Ira A. Yake (Box 15)
  - Lincoln
    - #356-Armstrong (Box 15)
    - #476-Burt McCullough Post (Box 15)
  - Livonia
    - #521-Price Brothers Company Post (Box 15)
  - Mackinac Island
    - #316-Wm. Alvin Beloungea (Box 15)
    - #514-Chapman-Belongea Post (Box 15)
  - Madison Heights
    - #254-Madison Heights Post (Box 15)
  - Manton
    - #332-Emery Derbyshire (Box 15)
  - Marenisco
    - #271-Presque Isle (Box 15)
  - Marine City
    - #127-Regan-Felgenauer (Box 15)
  - Marion
    - #302-Carl A. Bonham (Box 15)
  - Marlette
    - #162-Marlette (Box 15)
  - Marysville
    - #269-Marysville (Box 15)
  - McBain
    - #145-James B. Jackson (Box 15)
  - Michigamme
    - #238-Carl Anderson (Box 15)
    - #339-Carl Anderson (Box 15)
  - Middleville
    - #25-Leo A Miller (Box 15)
  - Millington
    - #289-Ray Henderson (Box 15)
  - Minden City
    - #291-McLeod Kelley (Box 15)
    - #503-Minden City (Box 15)
  - Monroe
    - #424-Maeco (Box 15)
  - Montgomery
    - #219-Tri-State (Box 15)
  - Morenci
    - #219-F. Russell Green (Box 15)
    - #241-Raymond R. Sebring (Box 15)
  - Morley
    - #312-Rosenweig-Knox (Box 15)
  - Mt. Clemens
    - #437-The King-Banks Elzy (Box 15)
  - Mt. Morris
    - #418-Russell Davis (Box 15)
    - #183-Russell Davis (Box 15)
    - #314-Martin C. Luther (Box 15)
  - Muskegon
    - #214-Harding-Johnson (African American) (Box 15)
    - #323-William Stoppels (Box 15)
    - #492-Phantom Guard (Box 15)
  - Muskegon Heights
    - #351-Harding Johnson (Box 15)
    - #405-Muskegon Heights (Box 15)
    - #532-Sherman Walker (Box 15)
  - Nahma
    - #224-Mercier (Box 15)
  - Napoleon
    - #549-Napoleon (Box 15)
  - Nashville
    - #113-Nashville (Box 15)
  - Newaygo
    - #100-Raymond Peters (Box 15)
  - Negaunee
    - #66-John H. Mitchell (Box 15)
  - New Buffalo
    - #169-Harry R. Kruger (Box 15)
  - Niles
    - #116-Bertrand (Box 15)
  - North Beach
    - #75-Patrick McCurdy (Box 15)
  - Olivet
    - #210-John R. Jacquette (Box 15)
    - #572-Kelley Shaw (Box 15)
  - Onway
    - #178-Leo E. Richmond (Box 15)
    - #238-Camp Presque Isle (Box 15)
    - #317-Forest Preston Jr. (Box 15)
  - Ontonagon
    - #40-Smith-Adams (Box 15)
  - Ortonville
    - #164-Richmond Scott (Box 15)
  - Otter Lake
    - #365-Children's Billet (Box 15)
  - Ovid
    - #154-Storrer-Bowlby (Box 15)
  - Owosso
    - #419-Crawford-Arnold Post (Box 15)
  - Palmer
    - #59-Palmer (Box 15)
  - Parisville
    - #347-Maurer (Box 15)
  - Parma
    - #292-Cyril R. Klein (Box 15)
  - Peck
    - #190-James F. Grimes (Box 15)
  - Pellston
    - #158-Pellston (Box 15)
  - Pentwater
    - #280-Victor Jensen (Box 15)
  - Perrinton
    - #238-Willoughby Smith (Box 15)
  - Pigeon
    - #23-Comprends (Box 15)
  - Pinconning
    - #313-Prybylski (Box 15)
  - Pinckney
    - #271-J. Ray Kennedy (Box 15)
  - Pleasant Ridge
    - #389-Pascoe-Crosthwaite (Box 15)
  - Plymouth